<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Films starring SLJ</title>
    <description>That&#39;s it</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:53:57 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:53:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hateful Eight</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;poster&quot;&gt;Poster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/thehatefuleight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Hateful Eight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plot&quot;&gt;Plot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years after the Civil War, bounty hunter Major Marquis Warren is transporting three dead bounties to the town of Red Rock, Wyoming. He hitches a ride on a stagecoach driven by a man named O.B. Jackson. Aboard is John Ruth, a bounty hunter known for bringing in outlaws alive to see them hang, and fugitive Daisy Domergue, whom Ruth is escorting handcuffed to him to Red Rock. Ruth is suspicious of anyone who might steal her to claim her substantial bounty. Ruth and Warren bond over Warren’s personal letter from Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Lost-Causer militiaman Chris Mannix, who claims he is travelling to Red Rock as the town’s new sheriff, persuades Ruth and Warren to let him on the stagecoach. Warren and Ruth form an alliance to protect each other’s bounties. Mannix and Warren almost come to blows over their controversial war records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group is forced to seek refuge from a powerful blizzard at Minnie’s Haberdashery, a stagecoach lodge. They are greeted by Bob, a Mexican who says owner Minnie is visiting her mother and left him in charge. The other lodgers are Oswaldo Mobray, a hangman; Joe Gage, a quiet cowboy travelling to visit his mother; and Sanford Smithers, a former Confederate general. Suspicious, Ruth disarms all but Warren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the group eats, Mannix surmises that Warren’s Lincoln letter is a forgery. Warren admits this, saying the letter buys him leeway with whites, outraging Ruth. Warren leaves a gun next to Smithers and provokes him into reaching for it by telling Smithers he tortured, raped and killed Smithers’ son. Warren shoots Smithers in “self-defense”, in revenge for Smithers’ execution of black soldiers at the Battle of Baton Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While everyone is distracted by the confrontation, someone seen only by Daisy poisons the brewing coffee. Ruth and O.B. drink it, vomit blood, and collapse. The dying Ruth attacks Daisy, but she kills him with his own gun. Warren disarms Daisy, holds the men at gunpoint and leaves her cuffed to Ruth’s corpse. Warren is joined by Mannix, whom Warren trusts because he nearly drank the poisoned coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warren executes Bob, deducing that he is an impostor who killed the lodge owners. When Warren threatens to execute Daisy, Gage admits he is the poisoner. A man hiding in the cellar shoots Warren in the groin. Mobray draws a concealed gun and shoots Mannix, who returns fire, wounding Mobray and forcing Gage against the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier that day, Bob, Mobray, Gage, and a fourth man, Jody Domergue, Daisy’s brother, arrive at Minnie’s Haberdashery and kill everyone but General Smithers. Jody tells Smithers they plan to ambush Ruth to rescue Daisy, and that his gang will spare Smithers if Smithers keeps quiet, as an extra lodger will make the setup more believable. The bandits dispose of the bodies, hide the evidence, and conceal guns around the lodge. As Ruth’s stagecoach arrives, Jody hides in the cellar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the present, Mannix and Warren, both seriously wounded, hold Daisy, Gage, and the dying Mobray at gunpoint. They force Jody out of the cellar by threatening to kill Daisy, and when he surrenders, Warren executes him. Daisy claims fifteen of her brother’s men are waiting in Red Rock to kill Mannix and ransack the town; if Mannix kills Warren and allows her to escape, the gang will spare him and let him claim the bounties of the deceased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Daisy and Mobray taunt Warren, Warren shoots Daisy in the foot, then Mobray in the leg, who eventually dies from his wounds. Gage draws a hidden revolver but is shot dead by Mannix and Warren. Warren tries to shoot Daisy but has run out of bullets. Mannix calls Daisy’s bluff and rejects her offer, but faints from blood loss. Daisy hacks off Ruth’s handcuffed arm and frees herself. As she reaches for a gun, Mannix regains consciousness, shoots, and wounds her. Warren persuades Mannix to hang her from the rafters in honor of Ruth. Afterward, as the two lie dying, Mannix reads aloud Warren’s forged Lincoln letter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 21:32:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2016-04/The-Hateful-Eight</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2016-04/The-Hateful-Eight</guid>
        
        
        <category>Films</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Captain America: The Winter Soldier</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;poster&quot;&gt;Poster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/captainamerica.img&quot; alt=&quot;Captain America&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plot&quot;&gt;Plot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years after the Battle of New York, Steve Rogers works in Washington D.C. for the 
espionage agency S.H.I.E.L.D. under Director Nick Fury, while adjusting to contemporary society.
Rogers and Agent Natasha Romanoff are sent with S.H.I.E.L.D.’s counter-terrorism S.T.R.I.K.E. team,
 led by Agent Rumlow, to free hostages aboard a S.H.I.E.L.D. vessel from Georges Batroc and his mercenaries. 
 Mid-mission, Rogers discovers Romanoff has another agenda: to extract data from the ship’s computers for Fury. 
 Rogers returns to the Triskelion, S.H.I.E.L.D.’s headquarters, to confront Fury and is briefed about 
 Project Insight: three Helicarriers linked to spy satellites, designed to preemptively eliminate threats. 
 Unable to decrypt the data recovered by Romanoff, Fury becomes suspicious about Insight and asks senior S.H.I.E.L.D. 
 official Alexander Pierce to delay the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his way to rendezvous with Maria Hill, Fury is ambushed by assailants led by a mysterious assassin called the Winter Soldier. 
Fury escapes to Rogers’ apartment, and warns Rogers that S.H.I.E.L.D. is compromised. After handing Rogers a flash drive containing 
data from the ship, Fury is gunned down by the Winter Soldier. Fury dies in surgery, and Hill recovers the body. The next day, 
Pierce summons Rogers to the Triskelion. When Rogers withholds Fury’s information, Pierce brands him a fugitive. Hunted by S.T.R.I.K.E., 
Rogers meets with Romanoff. Using data in the flash drive they discover a secret S.H.I.E.L.D. bunker in New Jersey, where they activate 
a supercomputer containing the preserved consciousness of Arnim Zola. Zola reveals that ever since S.H.I.E.L.D. was founded after World War
 II, Hydra has secretly operated within its ranks, sowing global chaos with the objective of making humanity willing to surrender its freedom in exchange for security. The pair narrowly escape death when a S.H.I.E.L.D. missile destroys the bunker,
  and realize that Pierce is Hydra’s leader within S.H.I.E.L.D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rogers and Romanoff enlist the help of former USAF pararescueman Sam Wilson, whom Rogers befriended, 
and acquire his powered “Falcon” wingpack. Deducing that S.H.I.E.L.D. agent Jasper Sitwell is a Hydra mole,
 they force him to divulge that Zola developed a data-mining algorithm that can identify individuals who might 
 become future threats to Hydra’s plans. The Insight Helicarriers will sweep the globe, using satellite-guided
  guns to eliminate these individuals. Rogers, Romanoff, and Wilson are ambushed by the Winter Soldier, who kills
   Sitwell. During the fight, Rogers recognizes the Winter Soldier as Bucky Barnes, his friend who was captured 
   and experimented upon during WWII. Hill manages to extract the trio to a safehouse where Fury, who had faked 
   his death, is waiting with plans to sabotage the Helicarriers by replacing their controller chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the World Security Council members arrive for the Helicarriers’ launch, Rogers broadcasts Hydra’s plot 
to everyone at the Triskelion. Romanoff, disguised as one of the Council members, disarms Pierce. Fury arrives and forces Pierce to unlock S.H.I.E.L.D’s database so that Romanoff can leak classified information, exposing Hydra to the public. Following a struggle, Fury kills Pierce. Meanwhile, Rogers and Wilson storm two Helicarriers and replace the controller chips, but the Winter Soldier destroys Wilson’s suit and fights Rogers on the third. Rogers fends him off and replaces the final chip, allowing Hill to take control and have the vessels destroy each other. Rogers refuses to fight the Winter Soldier in an attempt to reach his friend, but as the ship collides with the Triskelion, Rogers is thrown out into the Potomac River. The Winter Soldier rescues the unconscious Rogers before disappearing into the woods. With S.H.I.E.L.D. in disarray, Romanoff appears before a Senate subcommittee and Fury, under the cover of his apparent death, heads to Eastern Europe in pursuit of Hydra’s remaining cells. Rogers and Wilson decide to find the Winter Soldier, while Rumlow, who was a double agent for Hydra, is hospitalized following the Triskelion’s destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a mid-credits scene, Baron Wolfgang von Strucker, at a Hydra lab, proclaims that the “age of miracles” 
has begun as scientists examine an energy-filled scepter[N 1] and two prisoners: one with superhuman speed, 
the other with telekinetic powers. In a post-credits scene, the Winter Soldier visits a Bucky memorial at the Smithsonian Institution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2016-04/Captain-America-The-Winter-Soldier</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2016-04/Captain-America-The-Winter-Soldier</guid>
        
        
        <category>Films</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pulp Fiction</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;poster&quot;&gt;Poster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pulpfiction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pulp Fiction&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plot&quot;&gt;Plot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Prologue—The Diner”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple, Pumpkin and Honey Bunny, decide to rob a diner.
Prelude to “Vincent Vega and Marsellus Wallace’s Wife”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitmen Jules Winnfield and Vincent Vega are on their way to retrieve a briefcase from Brett, who has transgressed against their boss, gangster Marsellus Wallace. Vincent says Marsellus has asked him to escort his wife while Marsellus is out of town. They arrive at Brett’s place, where they confront him and two of his associates over the briefcase. Vincent finds the briefcase and Jules shoots one of Brett’s associates, then delivers a passage from the Bible before killing Brett with Vincent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Champion boxer Butch Coolidge accepts a large sum of money from Marsellus after agreeing to take a dive in his upcoming match. Vincent and Jules arrive to deliver the briefcase. The next day, Vincent purchases heroin from his drug dealer Lance. He shoots up to pass the day, then drives to meet Mrs. Mia Wallace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vincent and Mia head to a 1950s-themed restaurant and participate in a twist contest, then return to the Wallace house with the trophy. While Vincent is in the bathroom, Mia finds his heroin, mistakes it for cocaine, snorts it and overdoses. Vincent rushes her to Lance’s house, where they revive her with an adrenaline shot to her heart.
Prelude to “The Gold Watch”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butch recalls a visit from Vietnam veteran Captain Koons in his youth. Koons brought a gold watch passed down through three generations of Coolidge men since World War I; at the dying request of Coolidge’s father, Koons hid the watch in his rectum for two years to deliver it to Butch.
“The Gold Watch”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butch flees the arena, having double-crossed Marsellus and won the bout. The next morning, at the motel where he and his girlfriend Fabienne are lying low, Butch discovers she has forgotten to pack his father’s watch and flies into a rage. He returns to his apartment, retrieves the watch, and notices a gun on the kitchen counter. Hearing the toilet flush, Butch shoots Vincent dead after he exits the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Butch waits at a traffic light in his car, Marsellus walks by and recognizes him. Marsellus chases him into a pawnshop. The owner, Maynard, captures them at gunpoint and ties them up in a basement. Maynard is joined by Zed, a security guard; they take Marsellus to another room to rape him, leaving a silent figure in a bondage suit, “the gimp”, to watch Butch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butch breaks loose and knocks out the gimp. He is about to flee, but decides to save Marsellus. As Zed is raping Marsellus, Butch kills Maynard with a katana retrieved from the pawnshop. Marsellus retrieves Maynard’s shotgun and shoots Zed. Marsellus informs Butch that they are even, so long as he never tells anyone about the rape and departs Los Angeles forever. Butch returns to pick up Fabienne on Zed’s chopper.
“The Bonnie Situation”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Vincent and Jules execute Brett, another man bursts out of the bathroom and shoots wildly, missing every time; Jules and Vincent shoot him. Jules decides their lucky escape was a miracle, which Vincent disputes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Jules drives, Vincent accidentally shoots Marvin, one of Brett’s associates, in the face. They hide the car at the home of their associate Jimmie, who insists they deal with the problem before his wife Bonnie comes home. Marsellus sends his cleaner, Winston Wolfe, who orders Jules and Vincent to clean the car, hide the body in the trunk, and dispose of their bloody clothes. They drive the car to a junk yard and Jules and Vincent decide to get breakfast.
“Epilogue—The Diner”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the diner, Jules tells Vincent he plans to retire from his life of crime, taking their “miraculous” survival as a sign. While Vincent is in the bathroom, Pumpkin and Honey Bunny hold up the restaurant. When Jules holds Pumpkin at gunpoint, Honey Bunny becomes hysterical and trains her gun on him; Vincent returns with his gun trained on her. Jules recites the biblical passage, expresses ambivalence about his life of crime, and allows the robbers to take the cash and leave. Jules and Vincent leave the diner with the briefcase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2016-04/Pulp-Fiction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2016-04/Pulp-Fiction</guid>
        
        
        <category>Films</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Django Unchained</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;poster&quot;&gt;Poster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/djangounchained.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Django Unchained&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plot&quot;&gt;Plot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Texas 1858, the Speck brothers, Ace and Dicky, drive a group of black slaves on foot. Among the shackled slaves is Django, sold off and separated from his wife, Broomhilda von Shaft. The Speck brothers are stopped by Dr. King Schultz, a German dentist-turned-bounty hunter from Düsseldorf, who asks to buy one of the slaves. When he questions Django about his knowledge of the Brittle brothers, a group of outlaws for whom Schultz is carrying a warrant, Ace becomes irritated and threateningly aims his shotgun at Schultz. Schultz, a superior gunslinger, immediately kills Ace with a Fast draw. King insists on honourably paying Dicky a fair price for Django before leaving him at the mercy of the newly-freed slaves, who kill him and follow the North Star to freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Django can identify the Brittle brothers, Schultz offers him his freedom in exchange for help tracking them down. King first takes Django to a small town where he immediately murders the sheriff. Before a Marshall can arrest them King explains that the sheriff was actually a wanted man with a $200 bounty on him that the furious Marshall is now required to pay. After tracking and killing the Brittles, the liberated Django (adopting the surname “Freeman”) partners with Schultz through the winter and becomes his apprentice; Schultz discovers that Django has a natural talent for gunslinging. Schultz explains that he feels responsible for Django since Django is the first person he has ever freed, and felt morally obliged to help Django (whom he described as a “real-life Siegfried”) reunite with Broomhilda. Django, now fully trained, collects his first bounty, keeping the handbill for good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1859, Django and Schultz travel to Mississippi, where they learn the identity of Broomhilda’s owner: Calvin J. Candie, the charming but cruel owner of the Candyland plantation, where slaves are forced to fight to the death in brutal wrestling matches called “Mandingo fights”. Schultz, expecting Candie will not sell Broomhilda if they ask for her directly, feigns interest in purchasing one of Candie’s prized fighters for far more than the normal price. Schultz and Django meet Candie at his gentleman’s club in Greenville and submit their offer. Intrigued, Candie invites them to his ranch at Candyland. After secretly briefing the German-speaking Broomhilda, Schultz claims to be charmed by her and offers to buy her as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During dinner, Candie’s staunchly loyal house slave, Stephen, becomes suspicious of Schultz and Django’s motives. Deducing that Django and Broomhilda know each other and that the sale of the Mandingo fighter is a ruse, Stephen alerts Candie and admonishes him for his greed. Candie is angered at being fooled and having his time wasted, but contains his anger long enough to theatrically display his knowledge of phrenology, which he uses to theorize why slaves frequently fail to kill their owners, despite ample opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candie’s bodyguard, Butch Pooch, bursts into the room with his shotgun trained on the two bounty hunters, and Candie explodes in anger. He offers an alteration of the original deal, with Broomhilda taking the Mandingo fighter’s place at the same price, and threatens her death should the deal be rejected. Schultz agrees, and the papers for her freedom are drawn up and signed. Candie smugly insists that the deal be sealed through a handshake, which Schultz initially refuses. When Candie threatens again to kill Broomhilda, Schultz snaps and kills Candie with a concealed derringer. Butch kills Schultz and Django kills him in turn, and an extensive gunfight begins. Django guns down a great number of his opponents, but surrenders when Broomhilda is taken hostage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Stephen tells Django that he will be sold to a mine and worked to death. En route to the mine, Django proves to his escorts that he is a bounty hunter by showing them the handbill from his first kill. He convinces them that there is a large bounty for criminals hiding at Candyland, and promises that they would receive the majority of the money if they free him. The escorts release him and give him a pistol, which he uses to kill them before stealing a horse and returning to Candyland with a bag of dynamite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the plantation, Django kills more of Candie’s henchmen, takes Broomhilda’s freedom papers from the dead Schultz’s pocket, bids goodbye to his late friend and frees his wife from a nearby cabin. When Candie’s mourners return from his burial, Django kills the remaining henchmen and Candie’s sister Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly, releases the two remaining house slaves, and kneecaps Stephen. Django then ignites the dynamite that he has planted throughout the mansion, and he and Broomhilda watch from a distance as the mansion explodes with the incapacitated Stephen inside, before riding off together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2016-04/Django-Unchained</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2016-04/Django-Unchained</guid>
        
        
        <category>Films</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
